[roaring]
[narrator] Strange beasts
and monsters.
Vast riches.
Hidden treasures.
Evil haunts.
Uncharted frontiers.
“The mysterious unknown.”
The people who are captivated
by the magic in those words…
are called…
Hunters.
[theme song playing]
Okay, now!
[Menchi] The joy of discovering
something delicious.
And now you know what it feels like.
That feeling is
what we risk our lives for.
SHOWDOWN x ON x THE AIRSHIP
[narrator]
After clearing the Exam’s Second Phase
Gon and his friends
fly through the starry sky
toward the site of the Third Phase.
[man] I will now take the opportunity
to introduce myself properly
to the remaining 42 applicants.
I am Netero,
the Chairman of the Selection Committee
for this year’s Hunter Exam.
It’s a pleasure to meet all of you.
And I’m his secretary, Beans.
[Netero] I had originally planned
to make my appearance
during the Exam’s final phase
but, well seeing as how I’m already here…
I have to admit,
there’s nothing I love more
than this feeling of tension in the air.
So, I think I’ll stick around
for the remainder of the trip.
[laughs]
We are scheduled
to arrive at our destination
tomorrow morning
at 8:00 a.m. exactly.
You’ll find dinner waiting for you
in the dining hall.
You’re also welcome
to get some rest, of course.
You’re free to do as you please
until we contact you.
The evening is yours.
Hey come on, Gon!
Let’s go and explore the airship!
Yeah!
They’ve got so much energy!
Not me, though.
All I wanna do now is crash.
As do I.
However, there is one thing
that still concerns me.
[Leorio] Oh? What’s up?
[Kurapika] How many more phases
are there in the Exam?
Huh. Yeah, they haven’t said, have they?
As long as I’ve been doing this,
it’s averaged five or six.
Which means that we’ve still got
another three or four left to go.
Well, in that case we should
get some rest now, while we can.
Okay but I’d be careful if I were you.
Huh?
You heard the secretary, right?
He only told us when we’re arriving.
He didn’t say
that the Third Phase of the Exam
wasn’t gonna happen right here
on the airship itself.
And we’ll be notified, but who knows
if that’ll be at 8:00 a.m. or not?
Hold on. Are you serious?
I suppose that makes sense.
[Tonpa] You might wake up
and find out the Exam already took place
and you slept right through it.
If you wanna get to the next phase,
then ya better not let your guard down,
even up here. Understand?
C’mon, gimme a break.
Well. Thanks for the advice. See ya later.
We’ll be sure to keep it in mind.
Good luck to all of us, eh?
Psyched ‘em!
I bet they’re both so nervous
they won’t sleep a wink!
They’ll be worthless by morning.
[Kurapika] There’s no chance
the next phase
will take place on the airship.
If that were their intention,
they wouldn’t have told us
we were free to do as we pleased
and enjoy the amenities
but to stand by and wait for instructions.
[snoring]
[tapping]
[Menchi] So. How many applicants
do you think’ll make it this year?
You mean, who’ll pass the Exam?
[Menchi] Yep. Looks like we’ve got
a pretty impressive group here.
Though, I did try to fail them all, sure.
But still.
Gee, I don’t know.
I guess it depends on
what the other phases are.
That’s a good point.
I hadn’t thought of that.
But a few of ‘em stand out,
didn’t you notice?
And one even has this whole aura thing
going on.
What do you think, Satotz?
[Satotz] I’m inclined to agree.
I quite like the rookies this year.
Yeah! Same here!
I like number 294.
I really think he’s got a good shot
at winning.
[Satotz] I’m partial to number 99, myself.
He looks like a spoiled, selfish brat
if you ask me.
What about you, Buhara?
Who I think will pass?
Well, he’s not a rookie
but my money’s on number 44.
I’m sure you guys must’ve noticed it, too.
but when number 255 was throwing a fit,
44 was the one who looked
like he wanted to kill somebody.
He had this cold, intense bloodlust.
[Menchi] Of course, I noticed that.
How could I not?
It looked like
he could barely restrain himself.
Hold on, didn’t you realize?
He’s been like that
ever since we showed up.
I’ve had a bad feeling about him
this whole time.
Really?
Yeah.
He’s the real reason
I was so edgy during the Exam.
I mean, he kept trying
to pick a fight with me.
I had a similar experience.
He should be carefully monitored.
Though it pains me to admit this,
I feel we are all birds of a feather
with him.
But his affinity for darkness,
is infinitely stronger than ours.
We Hunters, as you know,
are constantly seeking out new rivals.
And the Hunter Exam
has no shortage of opponents,
each perfectly qualified
and worthy of respect.
And every now and then in our searches
we encounter someone...
Someone who chooses to surge forward
when you or I would opt for the brakes.
An anomaly of sorts.
[shudders]
[cook] Hey! Kids!
What are you doing?
Stay out of the kitchen!
Go eat in the dining hall with the others!
[Gon and Killua grunt]
[Killua] Huh?
Hey! Awesome!
-Gon, Look!
-What is it?
[Gon] Whoa!
-It’s like it’s covered in jewels!
-Yeah!
[Gon] Hey... so I was wondering…
[Killua] Huh?
[Gon] Your parents. Are they--
I mean… where are they?
[Killua] Hmm... They're alive. Probably.
[Gon] What do they do?
[Killua] They're assassins.
They both are?
That’s your response?
You really are a riot, aren’t ya?
You’re not the first person
I’ve told about my parents,
but you’re the first to take it seriously.
[Gon] But it’s true, isn’t it?
Why d’ya think that?
It’s just a hunch.
Weird.
Most of the time people only like me
because they can’t tell
if I’m serious or not.
[Gon] Huh?
[Killua]
I’m from a family of assassins, so yeah,
they’re all in the business of murder.
And my entire family...
they’ve got real high hopes for me.
But, y’know… I can’t stand it.
Who wants their whole life
mapped out for ‘em?
When I told them
I wanted to decide my own future,
they all flipped out. It was crazy!
My mom had tears
just streaming down her face
and she kept screaming at me
how I had the potential
to be a top assassin.
Horrible parents, right?
No wonder I’m rotten!
Then we started fighting,
so I slashed my mom in the face,
stabbed my brother in the side,
and ran away from home.
I’m sure they’re out for blood now.
-If they all come after me, I’ll kill ‘em!
-[laughs nervously]
When I get my license,
I’ll hunt ‘em down to the last one!
I’m willing to bet they’ve got
pretty hefty bounties on their heads.
Hm?
Hm...
[both gasp]
[Netero] Something wrong?
Mr. Netero…
You didn’t see anyone
coming from that side, did you?
No, I didn’t.
[Killua] When did he...
You’re fast. For an old timer.
Oh. That trick?
I just barely moved, that’s all.
What do you want?
You don’t have anything to do
‘til the last phase, isn’t that right?
Now, now, no need to be so unkind.
I just got a little bored,
so I decided to look for some company.
By the way, I’ve been meaning to ask you,
any thoughts on your first attempt
at the Hunter Exam?
Yeah! It’s a lot of fun!
There haven’t been any written tests yet,
and I was kinda worried about that.
I’m disappointed, honestly.
I expected this to be
a lot more challenging.
But I assume
the next phase’ll be more interesting.
Oh, well. We’ll see…
Let's go, Gon.
-Wait! Just a moment.
-[Killua] Hm?
Would you like
to play a little game with me?
Game?
And to make it interesting,
if you two can beat me,
I’ll make you Hunters on the spot.
Really?! I’ll play!
What do you say? Well?
HUNTER GLOSSARY
NETERO
Now, let’s go over the rules of the game.
All you have to do is simply
take this ball away from me.
If you can do that
before the airship arrives, you win.
So, let’s see…
We’re scheduled for an 8:00 a.m. arrival,
yes?
Well, that’s not too bad.
You still have nine hours left.
And feel free to use any tactics you want.
I will only defend. I promise.
Huh? That’s too easy!
It’s... barely even a game!
Then why not give it a try
and see if you’re right?
All we have to do is take the ball?
Yes.
Then, I’ll give it a shot.
Go right ahead.
He thinks I’m weak.
Oh?
I see a bunch of Killuas!
[Netero] One of the assassination arts…
"The Rhythm Echo."
It confuses the enemy with afterimages
created by a varying cadence of steps.
To think he’s already
mastered the technique at his age.
What a dreadful child!
Oh wow!
[Killua] He sure moves around a lot.
How old is this guy?
Is that all? How disappointing.
[annoyed grunt] In that case,
I’ll just have to slow him down!
Ow! His pivot leg!
[arrogant chuckle]
[groans]
[screaming in pain]
[pensive grunt]
[Netero] He certainly didn’t hold back
with that kick.
If I were an ordinary person,
it would have shattered my leg!
[Killua] Damn!
His legs are as hard as iron!
[grunts]
Killua! Tag me, tag me!
C’mon! It’s my turn!
[pensive grunt]
[Netero] This one seems
like a very honest young man.
I’m curious to see
what he has up his sleeve.
Okay!
[Netero]
Ah. I see he’s got a quick first step.
But he’s charging straight at me.
Very foolish indeed.
He’s still a child…
Wait, from above?
[Gon] Ow!
[Killua] Idiot!
We already know how high you can jump,
so you don’t have to go all out! Focus!
You had a chance!
He dropped his guard for a second!
[Netero] Heh, no kidding.
[recovering breath]
He may appear simple-minded
but he’s clearly using his head.
Well, that didn’t work.
[Netero] They should keep me entertained
until morning.
[snoring]
[chuckles]
Last time I saw those two,
they were pretty shaken up.
They were both so nervous,
I bet they aren’t getting a wink of sleep!
-[snoring]
-They’re snoring?!
[grunting]
[panting]
[Killua grunting]
[groans]
Ow, ow, ow!
You boys aren’t getting anywhere, huh?
Why don’t both of you
try attacking me at once?
[Killua grunts angrily]
Why, you--!
Okay! We gotcha now!
Not bad!
But still not good enough.
[laughs]
[Gon]
Mr. Netero hasn’t even broken a sweat!
-Ow!
[laughs]
[Gon] If we’re gonna beat him,
we’ve got to get creative.
Gotta say,
your attacks don’t amount to much.
[Netero groans in pain]
[Netero] What? He kicked off his shoe
to increase his range?
[grunts]
[surprised Netero groans in pain]
Now’s our chance!
I think not.
Oh! Sneaky kids!
[both] I’ve almost got it!
[both groan]
Well now….
Excellent teamwork!
You get an "A" for effort!
[Gon] You’re amazing, Mr. Netero!
Really amazing!
Ah, forget it.
I quit. Ya beat me, all right?
Oh… Quitting already?
Don’t quit! We’ve still got lots a time.
And besides, we came so close just now.
Come on. You’re really clueless,
aren’t ya?
It’s hopeless.
Think about it. The old guy’s barely used
his right hand or left leg.
He’s way too powerful for us, Gon.
We could keep at this for an entire year
and never get that ball.
Figured it out, did you?
And here I was thinking
I’d been pretty slick about it.
Oh! I get it now!
[Killua laughs]
You sure know how to piss me off, old man.
Let’s go, Gon!
Nah, I think I’m gonna play
a little longer.
[Killua] Huh?
Are you deaf? Didn’t you hear
what I just said?
Look! It’s pointless!
You’ll never get the ball from him!
S’okay. ‘Cause I don’t really care.
We’ve only used up half of the time limit.
I’m gonna see if I can get him
to use his right hand
before the rest of it runs out.
I see…
Fine. I get it.
Well, good luck.
I’m going to bed.
Hey, Mr. Netero.
[Netero] Hmm?
Can you tell me
how Killua did that thing he did?
You know, when he walked slow
and then there were a bunch of him?
That was...
a technique used by those
engaged in illegal activities.
You have no need at all to learn it.
As a matter of fact,
you should never try to learn it.
But it’s pretty impressive, huh?
Hmm. It requires an incredible
amount of training to master it.
Oh man, Killua really is something,
isn’t he?
-Nice try.
-[Gon chuckles nervously]
[Killua] Dammit. Now I’m in a bad mood.
Well, it is what it is.
[number 390] Hey, kid! Wait up!
[number 391] Yeah, where are your manners?
-[number 390] Hey!
-[number 391] Come back here!
If I hadn’t stopped when I did,
I probably would’ve ended up killing
the old man to get the ball.
[both grunt]
Ah. It looks like my little playmate
is picking up the pace a bit.
Now!
He’s feinting for the ball,
but he’s really going for my stomach!
Huh?
That hurt!
One more!
[Netero] Oh. If he head-butts me
in my stomach like that again,
he’ll shatter his skull!
But if I relax my muscles,
he might actually lay me out.
Hmm...
Best to avoid that.
Ah... did that kill him?
[grinning]
Gotcha! You just used your right hand!
Huh?
I did…
I did it! Yeah!
[Gon laughing]
Yay!
[snoring]
[Netero] Hello, Captain?
Yes, it’s me.
Is the flight going smoothly?
I really hate to ask you to do this…
Could you maybe slow the ship down?
Just a little?
[narrator] Netero had proposed the game
to kill time,
but as they played,
he saw something in Gon.
The airship and all 42
of the remaining applicants on board
are approaching the site
of the Exam’s Third Phase.
[theme song playing]
[Gon] Next time:
“Decision x By x Majority Rule?”
-[Killua] Major, major--
-[Gon] Major trouble!
[Killua] Trouble maker!